Shav Vimalendiran

AI & DATA SCIENTIST

I decided to pursue a career in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning (having graduated with a degree in Chemical Engineering) after I tried my hand at using Python while training my own StyleGAN to artificially generate artwork. As someone who loves to paint, I value creativity and attention-to-detail in everything I do, and this was the perfect creative outlet that values and leverages these skills, but also the analytical, interpersonal, technical and problem-solving skills I have honed during my time as a Chemical Engineer. This background was also invaluable when applying Ai and ML solutions to the manufacturing industry.

SUMMARY

I obtained a Master's degree (First Class Honours) in Chemical Engineering (MEng) from Imperial College London in 2021. Following my graduation, I decided to begin training with futureproof to upskill as a Full Stack Developer in order to kick-start my career in coding.

The projects I've completed to date have prepared me for effectively and quickly developing, training and deploying Al projects as part of a dev team. Since October 2021, I have spent my time implementing digital innovation for Apollo as part of a small group focussed on digital innovation using Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning. I have managed projects set to solve complex business problems and process transformations with the ultimate goal of significant financial benefits, while responding directly to specific business requirements, problems and inefficiencies.

I am specialized in Deep Learning; with experience building neural network architectures such as CNN's, Residual networks, U-Nets, RNN's, GRU's, LSTMs, Transformers, and have Implemented Industry best-practises for building deep learning applications effectively. By applying these concepts and understanding their industry applications using Python and TensorFlow, I have tackled real-world problems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Apollo & SaturnF1 (Digital Innovation Hub) | AI & Data Scientist | October 2021 - Present

- Built Predictive Models to increase asset utilisation, built Computer Vison Models poised for Detection, bounding and Semantic segmentation of defects and have taken part in deriving insights from unused data using Machine learning.
- Experience building neural network architectures such as Convolutional Neural Networks, Residual networks, U-Nets, Recurrent Neural Networks, GRU's, LSTMs, Transformers
- Software Engineering background knowledge enabled smooth deployment

Futureproof | Software Engineer | June 2021 - September 2021

- 13-week bootcamp covering the main areas of web development, including JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Databases, Cyber Security, TDD, SQL, Node/Express and Python.
- Pair programming projects utilised a collaborative Git workflow to develop applications

Splento | Internship | Visual Tech Start-up | June 2020 – July 2020

- Built and drove traffic to product pages using Search Engine Optimisation (SEO), PR Campaigns and Marketing skills
- Utilised written communication and created 360 VR videos in Premiere Pro for the purposes of content marketing
- Built upon transferable sales skills by listening, negotiating, persevering, communicating and being attentive.

EDUCATION

Imperial College London | Oct 2017 - June 2021

MEng Chemical Engineering, IChemE Accredited - First Class Honours

Queen Elizabeth's Boys School, Barnet | September 2010-2017

A-Level - Biology (A*), Chemistry (A*), Maths (A*), Physics (A), Further Maths AS (a) **GCSE -** 11 A*'s (including Maths, English and Sciences), 1 A

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Core Stack

JavaScript - HTML - CSS

Testing

Jest – SuperTest – React Testing Lib Pytest

API's & Backend

Express.js - Node.js

Databases, Authentication & Cybersecurity

Node.js - MongoDB - Docker - SQL PostgreSQL - Bcrypt

UI

React – Redux – Webpack – Babel – JSX React Router - Tailwind CSS

Python

Python – Flask – Django – NumPy Pandas – TensorFlow – Keras - Pytorch

Other

MATLAB – Git – GitHub – LaTeX GAMS – Solidworks – Photoshop Illustrator – Premiere Pro – InDesign aws – GSAP - JWT Tokens